[Genius Girlfriend]
[Episode 1]
The scorching sun,
the balmy sea breeze,
and the refreshing waves
keep this city looking like summer
all the time.
After my college graduation,
I chose to pursue a doctoral degree
on campus
and stay in this city.
Perhaps, subconsciously, I felt
that as long as I stayed here,
that summer from yesteryear
would never end.
Have you familiarized yourself
with the themed presentation
you'll give in a few days?
Yes, it's all set.
I'm ready to get on stage anytime.
Electronic devices
are highly affordable nowadays.
If you like this kind of digital watch,
why not replace it with a smart band?
It can track your sleep and heart rate.
It's different.
You have no idea.
This watch
used to have stars on its display.
But it broke two years ago.
Who would wear a watch
that can't tell time?
I would.
When Jiang Yubai gave me this watch,
he said
he had an identical one.
When the two watches
approached each other,
shining stars
would appear on the dial plates.
Although mine no longer tells time,
and the owner of the other watch
already vanished into the crowd,
I'm still wearing it,
as if I'm carrying a silent universe
on the wrist.
But, Jiang Yubai,
we have been out of contact
for five years.
Where on earth are you?
[Qingbei University]
Have you heard?
Today, Dr. Lin from our university
will give us a lecture.
Really?
I heard she was recommended
for admission to our univesity.
Here she comes.
Ms. Lin is so pretty.
[Qingbei University]
She really is.
She's not only an overachieving scholar
as I expected, but also a gorgeous lady.
[Qingbei University]
[Quantum Bits and Computers]
Today's lecture is about
quantum bits and computers.
A classical computer bit is like a switch—
it's either 0 or 1.
But a quantum bit,
on the other hand,
is more like a spinning top rotating
in two opposite directions simultaneously.
[The superposition state of a qubit]
Mathematics has demonstrated
that such superposition
[The perfect description in math]
can be perfectly described
by a vector in a Hilbert space.
What's going on?
[Quantum Bits and Computers]
On this ordinary afternoon,
the stars surprisingly showed up again.
The slight heat from the dial plate
resembles the warmth
that has never cooled down
deep in my memory.
You told me that you wouldn't be far away
as long as the stars were sparkling.
Jiang Yubai,
have you always been around?
Have you
never ever left?
[The year of 2004]
[Class 1, Grade 4]
Everyone,
today, we'll learn an ancient poem
titled
"Sitting Alone on Jingting Mountain."
I will read it once,
and you'll repeat after me.
"Sitting Alone on Jingting Mountain."
Written by Li Bai from Tang Dynasty.
Humans are social creatures.
This is common biological knowledge.
But before I grew to 10 years old,
the date of my social life
had always been unusual.
Mom, I finished the calculation.
I could do mental math
for a supermarket's daily cash flow
with zero error.
Within 30 seconds, I could
solve the final Math Olympiad question.
What baffled me was
why all the others
could make friends so easily.
Even after a nasty brawl,
they could get chummy again.
But in all my years of school,
I didn't even have a desk mate.
It was the first time
I saw a shooting star.
At that very moment,
I made a wish.
I want to be a strong
and optimistic person.
I also want to have a good friend—
someone who gets me and has my back,
for whom I'll do the same.
I hope my wish will soon come true.
Little did I expect that after that day,
there was really
a change in my life.
[Fourth Grade Office]
Ms. Wu, look,
this is Yubai's transcript
from when he studied in Singapore.
He got straight A's.
What an outstanding student Yubai is.
Ms. Wu, I settle for nothing
less than first.
How ambitious.
However,
it's no easy task to take
first place in this school.
Ms. Wu, I'll work hard.
[Name: Lin Zhixia] [Grade: 4] [Rank: 1]
Alright, class.
Quiet down, please.
I have an announcement to make.
A new transfer student
will join us in this semester.
His name is Jiang Yubai.
So your name's from this verse,
"Against the blue river, the birds
appear more white; Amid the green hills,
the flowers blaze with light."
Jiang Yubai
spent three years attending
elementary school in Singapore.
If he ever meets a problem,
should you or should you not help him?
We should.
Alright, Jiang Yubai,
take a seat over there.
Everyone, take out your textbooks.
The class begins now.
Why don't you say anything?
Hello.
My name is...
Jiang... Jiang... Jiang... Jiang...
Jiang Yubai.
"Jiang Jiang Jiang Jiang Yubai"?
Then you may call me
"Lin Lin Lin Lin Lin Zhixia."
Midterm exams are next week.
Make sure you review the lessons well
this weekend.
Got it?
Got it.
Class dismissed.
Stand up.
Goodbye, Ms. Wu.
Lin Zhixia,
I'll outscore you in the upcoming tests.
Are you saying
that you'll definitely beat me
in the upcoming midterm exams
and rank first
in the grade?
This time, I will definitely...
I mean, I'll probably
and possibly
take first place in the grade.
Jiang Yubai,
we just became desk mates.
I don't think you have
a thorough understanding of me yet.
How about this?
Let's make a bet.
If you end up ranking first in the grade,
I'll call you "Mr. Jiang."
But if I rise to top instead,
you'll call me "Ms. Lin"
as a gesture of respect.
What do you think?
I'm in.
[Jiang Yubai]
[Score: 100] [Score: 100] [Score: 100]
I guess I won't get to call you "Ms. Lin."
What a pity.
No.
You'll have to call me "Ms. Lin."
Lin Zhixia,
I didn't lose to you.
[Lin Zhixia]
[Score: 100] [Score: 100] [Score: 100]
[Added: 5 extra points]
I can't believe
you wrote the final essay
in classical Chinese.
Good for you!
Ms. Lin.
What? What did you just call me?
[Class 1, Grade 4]
I just flipped another one over!
You're quick.
Okay. Watch me!
It was really flipped back.
Can I play with you guys?
No. Go away.
Why?
Because I said no.
Scram.
Ji Fa's army.
I have two Shen Gongbao cards.
I just flipped it.
The contact area is too large.
Try tapping the corner of the card.
The chances of flipping it will be higher.
I'll give it a try then.
Lin Zhixia, aren't you being annoying?
Go away, or I'll show you no mercy.
It really flipped.
This card is mine now!
Lin Zhixia, you weirdo.
You're not leaving, are you?
Fine. We'll go play somewhere else!
Come on, let's go.
Did you make this?
The paper planes I make
always fly far and hit the target.
In the school I used to go to,
I even won first prize
in a paper plane competition.
Impressive.
Lin Zhixia, what's on your mind?
Jiang Yubai,
close your eyes.
When your eyes are closed,
your sense of hearing
becomes particularly sharp.
You can tell the sound
of the wind, crackling leaves,
and the chirping of sparrows.
Now, I'm wondering
if sparrows have consciousness.
Why are you wondering about that?
Jiang Yubai,
have you ever thought about your origin?
With your eyes closed,
can you feel your true self?
I often contemplate this:
I am me,
but who am I exactly?
I've been bothered by this question
for a long time.
I don't have an answer.
Jiang Yubai, do you?
Zeqiu, Zeqiu!
Zeqiu!
Zeqiu, I've got news.
I have a desk mate now.
He even initiates conversations
with me.
Zeqiu, did you hear me?
Yes, I did.
You've got a desk mate.
You're really bugging me.
I need to do my homework now.
Zeqiu, there's another way
to solve this question.
It's much simpler.
You think you know everything?
I don't need you to tutor me.
Then why don't you
go for a simpler solution?
You should listen carefully
when others speak.
My desk mate listens to me.
Does he... understand what you say?
No, not a single word.
Alright. Alright.
Whoever sits next to you
will end up getting crazy.
It's physics.
Can you understand that stuff?
Of course I can.
All I need is some more time.
Jiang Yubai,
maybe you should stay away
from Lin Zhixia.
I think
you're being infected by her.
Lin Zhixia is not a virus.
How can I be infected?
It seems to me that the way you speak
is more and more like hers.
Before you completely turn into her,
please get a new desk mate soon.
We'll see about that.
Jiang Yubai.
Are you competing with Ding Yan
for the position of Lin Zhixia's tagalong?
The two of you
are Tagalong No. 1 and Tagalong No. 2!
I'm not!
Look at
that physics book.
What elementary schooler studies physics?
Only Lin Zhixia does.
She's a weirdo.
You're the weirdo's desk mate.
You freaky tagalong!
What did you just say?
Jiang Yubai, what are you doing?
You want a fight?
Who's having a fight?
Zhou Bufeng, Jiang Yubai,
what were you doing?
What got you into a fight?
Speak up, or go stand outside
as punishment.
You freaky tagalong.
Jiang Yubai, tell me
what happened.
Ms. Wu, this is all that weirdo's fault.
She's not a weirdo!
Did I ask you, Zhou Bufeng?
Jiang Yubai!
Jiang Yubai,
will you still be my desk mate?
Of course I will.
I won't be a deserter.
Then I'd like to officially invite you
to be a specimen
for my observation of humans.
What?
I've always wanted to figure out
how ordinary people think and live.
Since you transferred here,
you've quickly fraternized with everyone,
even including me.
I'm wondering...
if you were scared
when you spoke up for me just now.
Were you angry when our classmates
hurled those rude remarks at you?
I...
Also,
when you came across something
related to the Hilbert space,
what was your immediate reaction?
Among all classmates,
only you would listen to me
as I bring up these topics,
though you never understand what I say.
In time, I will.
Most importantly,
Jiang Yubai, you are different
from any other classmate.
That's why I'm so eager to study you.
Look!
[The Human Observation Diary
is a preliminary research review]
[on ordinary humans' thinking modes.]
[Through observing
the author's desk mate, Jiang Yubai]
You want to study me
[the author hopes to further explore
the mindsets of ordinary humans]
[and the limitations
on their thinking patterns]
because I am an ordinary human?
Yes.
Lin Zhixia,
is your birthday coming up?
Yes, in a week.
Really? Well then...
[Novel Questions for Physics Contests]
Take all these books as a gift.
[Compilation of Questions
for Physics Contests]
[Compilation of High-Frequency Questions
All of them?
I've already read them through
and got the gist.
All the answer pages were torn out.
Jiang Yubai,
I can't believe you could master
so much knowledge
without answer pages.
You're amazing.
I'm totally defeated by you.
I've already read them through
and got the gist.
Besides, all the answer pages
were torn out.
All were torn out?
Yes.
Not an answer page is left in each book.
After all, I don't need answers.
I-I'm sorry.
Actually, Lin Zhixia,
I didn't throw the answer pages away.
I'll give them to you tomorrow.
Jiang Yubai,
thank you.
This is the first time I've received
a birthday gift from a classmate.
Purely unprecedented.
No one has treated me like this.
These are all my favorite books.
Jiang Yubai, you're so nice.
But the answer pages are gone.
It's fine.
I never look at standard answers.
The logic behind them
is completely different from mine.
All I want to do is find problems.
Problems help me think.
The process of thinking matters most.
Jiang Yubai, you know me so well.
Thank you again.
This is the best gift I've ever received.
Jiang Yubai, I announce,
from now on,
you are my friend,
my best friend.
Your best friend?
This year's autumn trip
will take place at the aquarium
this Saturday.
The fee is 76 yuan per person.
Tell your parents about it after school.
If you're not going, let me know.
Got it?
Got it.
Alright. Class dismissed.
Stand up!
Goodbye, Ms. Wu.
Alright, let's keep moving forward.
See the silver fish here?
What are they called?
It's called "silver dollar fish."
Come on, keep up.
Lin Zhixia,
you two had better not fall behind.
Keep up with us!
Jiang Yubai,
he just spoke to me.
You're happy when someone speaks to you?
Yes.
I think he wants to make friends with me.
Didn't you say
I am your best friend?
Yes,
you are.
But I also want to have more good friends.
Well...
That's a chubby fish.
Is "chubby" its name?
No, this is the humphead wrasse,
belonging to class Actinopterygii,
the order Perciformes,
the suborder Labroidei,
and the family Labridae.
It can be found mainly
in the Indian Ocean to the Pacific Ocean.
It has a mild temperament.
An adorable kind of fish, I'd say.
It's not called "chubby."
But I still consider it chubby.
This one's even chubbier.
Professor Shen.
The coral reproduction in the aquarium
has been less than ideal,
with a high mortality rate of larvae.
We suspect
there are unstable internal water flows
with unpredictable local micro-turbulence.
It's quite a tricky issue.
We really don't have a clue.
"Micro-turbulence"?
What is that?
Suppose you're stirring a cup of water
quickly and randomly,
the irregular and hard-to-see vortices
generated therein
are called micro-turbulence.
It's just like an invisible stirring rod.
Then what does it have to do with corals?
Mature corals may not fear it.
But for baby corals,
getting bumped around all the time
is like experiencing earthquakes
every day.
This way, they won't be able to
settle down and grow.
Little girl,
do you have any ideas as to
how this problem can be solved?
By installing artificial coral reefs,
I suppose.
When micro-turbulence passes
through the reefs,
it'll be broken down
into gentler currents,
reducing the damage.
Plus, The cavities and leeward sides
of these artificial reefs
will create
a still-water zone
where the current is almost zero,
and hence offer a safe haven
for coral larvae.
In other words,
from the perspective
of energy dissipation,
building a buffer structure
is a simple and effective solution, right?
How old are you?
What's your name?
My name is Lin Zhixia.
I'm in fourth grade.
Alright, Lin Zhixia.
This is my business card.
If you are truly interested in the ocean,
you're welcome to visit my lab
on the weekend.
Professor Shen, I have read your papers.
This is my best friend, Jiang Yubai.
Can I bring him along to your lab?
Yes, of course.
Our teacher is waiting for us.
Professor Shen, we have to go now.
See you.
Jiang Yubai, look.
Jiang Yubai,
look, the anglerfish is even uglier
than it appears in the book.
It...
Jiang Yubai?
Jiang Yubai!
Ms. Wu!
Where are you?
Lin Zhixia, look!
What kind of fish is this?
Lin Zhixia?
Lin Zhixia!
The distance between here and the exit
is no more than 20 meters.
I can make it.
I can make it there.
Lin Zhixia!
Are you crying?
Giant manta rays are not cute at all.
Come on. Let's go find our classmates
and teacher.
Come on, I'll lead the way.
♪ Let's run away ♪
♪ No turn to black ♪
♪ Your love will carry us
through the night ♪
♪ You and I ♪
♪ Long last night ♪
Get a move on. Time to assemble!
We're going to take photos.
Hurry up, kids!
Hurry up.
Jiang Yubai, Lin Zhixia, be quick!
Come on. Start running already.
Gather around. Stand in three rows.
Three rows. Pick your own spot.
Listen to me. Get ready.
Three, two, one, cheese!
Cheese!
Ms. Shen.
Is Lin Zhixia highly talented?
Yes, she's very talented.
And she's gifted
in a way that few people are.
It's a compliment for her.
Why are you so happy?
Well,
having a strong rival
means I'm strong too, right?
Right. When you grow up,
you'll come to realize
that having friends and rivals
is a blessing in life.
Lin Zhixia,
you know what?
When high-energy particles collide,
new matter is created.
I know that.
In the instant of collision
between protons running at light speed,
each carrying its total energy,
what bursts forth is not destruction,
but a brand new star.
Let's do that too.
What?
I mean,
confrontation and collaboration
are essentially a double helix.
How about we work hard together
for an admission
to the best junior high school?
Jiang Yubai, do you know
about time capsules?
Time capsules?
Let's write down our wishes.
When we get to junior high,
we'll come back and open the capsules.
What do you think?
Teachers said
that a plant's growth relies on sunshine.
I think Jiang Yubai and I grew up
relying on each other's support.
He told me jokes,
and I tutored him on theorems.
It was like two leaves
sharing the same ray of sunshine.
When we buried the capsules, he said
we'd bask in the sun again together.
We promised each other
that we would remain best friends
for longer than forever.
[Examination Seating Arrangement]
[Fourth to sixth grade]
Great!
We'll be in the same exam room.
That's wonderful.
[Examination Seating Arrangement]
Jiang Yubai!
Jiang Yubai, there you are.
You know what? We are assigned
to the same exam room.
Yubai, hurry! We need to go now.
Mom, give me a second!
Jiang Yubai, what's the matter?
I-I'm sorry.
Lin Zhixia,
I can't take the exam.
I'm moving
to another city.
Do you mean
we can't go to junior high together?
Yubai, we're heading to the airport.
Say bye to your classmate now.
♪ With every breath, the shadows creep ♪
My mom is rushing me.
I have to go.
♪ The devil in disguise ♪
This is my QQ number.
Make sure you send me a friend request.
♪ Talking the sweetest lies ♪
♪ It tries to drown me in my sleep ♪
Jiang Yubai!
♪ And comes like a tide ♪
Lin Zhixia, we'll meet again.
♪ It hurts, but I'm too tired to hide ♪
I haven't defeated you yet!
♪ Please hold me, help me
walk out of this endless night ♪
♪ Lost the light and power ♪
♪ Lost my will to fight ♪
♪ Can you stay by my side ♪
Didn't we agree
to go to junior high together?
We promised to go to junior high together.
♪ Be my light knight ♪
♪ Let's run away ♪
Jiang Yubai...
♪ Towards the light ♪
Jiang Yubai said,
if parallel universes truly exist,
♪ With you, I'll win this fight ♪
then we would be friends
in each universe.
♪ Let's run away ♪
We promised to bathe in the sun together
every day from then on.
♪ No turn to black ♪
♪ Your love will carry us
through the night ♪
I thought the sun would never
take a day off.
But that summer,
♪ You and I ♪
it took a long leave.
My best friend, Jiang Yubai,
♪ Long last night ♪
disappeared from my world.
♪ You and I ♪
♪ Will eventually start a new life ♪
[Five years later]
Zhixia,
school starts tomorrow, right?
I just fetched some new stationary
from my family's store.
Okay.
Zeqiu.
Knocking on the door
is a way to ask for permission.
But before I granted it, you already
barged into my room.
What's the point of all that knocking?
Speak up.
I want to use the computer.
No.
Please let me use it for a bit.
Not a chance.
I'm begging you.
Please let me use it for a bit.
It won't take long.
Not way.
Look, here's the thing.
My best friend is going to study
at No. 1 High School.
We will probably be placed
in the same class.
I left him a message some time ago.
I wonder if he has replied to it.
If you let me use the computer,
I promise I'll man the store
and listen to you more.
No.
Cramming on your holiday homework, huh?
Do you need my help?
Lin Zhixia,
I'm previewing the courses
for the new semester.
Did I ask for your help with my homework?
The way you talk
explains why you don't have a friend.
You know?
How do I not have a friend?
My friend will transfer to our school
when the semester begins.
Okay, let's not talk about this.
We weren't in the same school before.
But you'll be at No. 1 High School
when the new semester begins.
While you're there,
do not tell anyone
that I'm your older brother.
Why?
Many questions in this world
cannot be answered.
Just don't ask.
You mean we won't be
siblings anymore
when I go to No. 1 High School?
Lin Zhixia, you've grown up.
It's time you had your own friends.
Stop clinging to me, alright?
Fine, I will.
I won't acknowledge you as my brother.
But don't you forget
many people in the vicinity
also go to No. 1 High School.
Tang Tingting and Duan Qiyan both know
you're my brother.
You can't escape your fate.
On this planet,
[Human Observation Diary]
most people just cross paths.
Only a few stay for a lifetime.
In the fourth grade,
over those 275 days,
we became bosom friends from strangers.
Up till today, it has been five years.
[Human Observation Diary]
I wonder if that rare miracle
will happen
for me again.
[Human Observation Diary]
Attention, all students!
Attention, all teachers!
Lin Zeqiu is my older brother.
I often help him with his homework.
He ranked tenth in his class
simply because I tutored him
back in junior high.
My older brother is my student.
My older brother is my student!
She left so early?
Today is the first day of school.
Nobody is allowed to be late.
Are you silly or what, Duan Qiyan?
You're running late
on the first day of school.
I asked around.
The terrible Director Sui
is on duty today.
Aren't you also running late?
Not if I go faster than you!
[Problem Solving Challenge]
Who's that girl?
Do you know her?
Her name is Jin Baihui,
last year's top student.
She also made it to the youth talent class
in Beijing.
But after studying there
for about six months,
she still couldn't adapt
so she came back.
Then she repeated a grade
and got into the experimental class.
She's said to be
a super test-taking machine.
Please let me through.
Chunlei, what are you doing here?
Class is about to begin.
Aren't we getting new textbooks today?
We can get that stuff anytime.
But this rare clash of titans
is not to be missed.
The former top student
of the experimental class,
namely the boy who made it
to the Yao Class of Qingbei University,
left a question here
before his graduation—
[Problem Solving Challenge]
the Linglong Formation. Have you heard?
These girls are trying to crack it now.
[Battle]
Gosh.
Case analysis.
Identifying the dominant term.
It's hard to come up with this approach.
Besides, it involves so much calculation.
Look, in just a moment,
she has almost filled the entire board.
As expected of her,
solving problems is as easy as breathing.
So enviable.
I was asking about that other girl.
You meant Lin Zhixia?
She went to the same junior high school
with us.
Back then,
we liked to give top students like her
nicknames.
We called the boys "Masters,"
and girls "Immortals."
Lin Zhixia was the brightest
of all immortals in the highest heaven.
Impressive.
Geniuses always act like geniuses.
Hold on.
Where's the calculation process?
Without that,
who knows if you peeped at my answer
and calculated a bit faster than me?
I used the equation of the hyperbola
and integrated algebra with geometry.
It was a simple process.
No need for these many complicated steps.
You call my way of solving it
"complicated"?
I mean, there are various ways
to solve this math problem.
Your answer is correct.
The difference
is just that you made 15 steps,
while I made five.
Humiliating. This is utterly humiliating.
On the very first day of school,
Jin Baihui got crushed without mercy.
As expected of Lin Zhixia,
she's always direct in what she does.
Let me help you improve it.
Let's go. Scatter, guys.
Class is beginning. Let's go.
[Constantly Strive to Become Stronger;
Strive to Be Number One]
We're desk mates again.
This is great.
These seats are taken.
[Reading Corner]
Why did you do that?
I merely made it into
the experimental class in last place.
Behind us, there is already an "Immortal."
If Lin Zhixia took the seat
in front of me,
wouldn't I be crushed
like a sandwich cookie?
Human Observation Diary
[Bulletin Board]
Here.
It has one here too.
The inside is like this.
[Bulletin Board]
Hello, everyone,
welcome to the experimental class.
My name is Kong Yuanyuan,
your homeroom teacher,
as well as your math teacher.
Now I will start calling the roll
by student numbers.
Take this chance
to get to know each other,
will you?
Okay.
Lin Zhixia.
Here I am.
So you are Lin Zhixia.
Good.
Jiang Yubai.
Jiang Yubai?
Is he not here?
Chen Zhenghao.
Here.
Wang Qingyu.
May I come in?
Being late on the first day, huh?
What's your name?
Jiang Yubai.